Syeda Ruhina Ahmed

Aditya Apartments, Mehdipatnam, Hyderabad, Telangana, India, 500028 +91 7997106673 / +91 9441106959 sruhy99@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/syeda-ruhina

PROFILE

Process trainer having more than four years' experience in various settings, teaching both large and small groups in different locales. 100% success rate in designing, developing, and delivering effective training programmes while incorporating educational technologies to provide both on-site and virtual training. Capable of organizing and directing team-building activities and training sessions for client & higher management.

EDUCATION

Dr. B.R. Ambedkar Open University Hyderabad India January 2020 - June 2022 Masters in Zoology **Concentration:** Zoology & Aquaculture

Osmania University Hyderabad India

Bachelors in Genetics June 2017- March -2019 Concentration: Genetics, Zoology & Chemistry

WORK EXPERIENCE

 Cognizant Technology Solutions (Google Maps) India Global Policy Specialist

January 2023 – September 2023

- o On a daily basis, responded to product related policy queries Globally covering sites: HYD , DUB, TOK, KUL and MNL
- o Conducted an extensive analysis of public relations policies and PII risk management strategies; identified areas of weakness and implemented revised policies, reducing potential data breaches by 50%
- o Overseeing implementation of new policies by collecting the data about the operational impact of any changes
- o Suggesting improvements by bringing in 80–90% of user happiness while highlighting around 25% of the effects of prior policies in data reports.
- Cognizant Technology Solutions (Google Maps) India

Process Trainer

December 2022 - November 2021

o Facilitated 15+ New Hire Training batches comprising of 20-25 new joiners in each batch o Conducted 10+ training interventions to mitigate the errors by bringing in 80 -90% improvement o Designed more than 50 different kinds of material, including screencasts, crispers, GIFs, and decks. o Overall trained 600+ operators in cross trainings and workflow trainings

Cognizant Technology Solutions (Google Maps) India

Senior Process Executive

November 2021 - April 2021

- o Handling PO issues and concerns by providing resolutions per policy
- o Maintained user satisfaction with forward thinking strategies focused on addressing user needs and

Cognizant Technology Solutions (Google Maps) India

Quality Analyst

March 2021 - March 2020

- o Provided regular updates to Team Leadership on Quality metrics by communicating consistency problems which helped in 70-80% of error reduction
- o Delivered exceptional training and hands on motivation to 50+ team members to enhance 100% user satisfaction
- o Created and carried out test plans to make sure to bring down the escalation by 50%

• Cognizant Technology Solutions (Google Maps) India

Process Executive

February 2020 - August 2019

o Managing 100% user calls and providing support over calls and chats and updating accurate business information in Google Maps Front

ACHIEVEMENTS

• Always striving, never settling

o For the dedication, enthusiasm and commitment show

- Seeking data, building knowledge
 - o For being an exceptional performer
- Working as one
 - o Driving operational excellence
- Fantastic Trainer Skills
 - o For training delivery, governance and reporting

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

CTS Google Maps, Hyderabad, India

Process Trainer, Google Manila Team

o Facilitated 5+ New Hire Training batches comprising of 25-30 new joiners in each batch o Developed 25+ training content to address skill gaps in operators

CTS Google Maps, Hyderabad, India

Process Trainer, Google Manila Team

o Initiated a decision tree dashboard "Jupiter" in coordination with the PEX and Engg Team to bring down the error trend by showing 100% improvement

• Cognizant Technology Solutions Hyderabad, India

Outreach, Cognizant Team

o Volunteered in three separate communities' social initiatives programmes that benefited more than 50 people

- CREST Trainer Development Program July 2022
- Six Sigma, White Belt January 2023
- Email Etiquette March 2023

SKILLS

- Content Creation using all different apps like Canva, Wix etc.,
- Professional document production with Microsoft Word & Excel
- Collaborative document and spreadsheet creation and editing with Google Docs and Sheets
- Planning & Coordination

TOOLS

- Supermario
- Buganizer & Guts
- Pushpin Beta, Legacy, Dev, Experiments, Issue Admin
- Speakeasy

INTERESTS

- Content Creation
- Data Analysis
- Blogging